ﾍｯ 冗談じゃねえよ｡
ﾃﾒｴの筋 曲げるくらいなら
死んだほうが ﾏｼだ！
おい ﾂﾈよ 男だったら
背中で語れや｡
＜生き残るのは
やくざか えいりあんか!?＞
(雄たけび)
えいりあんが
なんぼのもんじゃ～い！
[Trailer]
[Starring Jo Otononaji
[Note: Name literally means "adult circumstances"]
No way!
I'd rather die than bend my principles!
[The time to fight is now.]
Aliens?! It's all over!
Yakuza? Or aliens? Which one will survive?
Alien vs. Yakuza
[Alien vs. Yakuza」
[Now playing」
Hey, Otsune. A man talks with his back.
[“Alien vs. Yakuza” starring Jo Otonanoji a.k.a. “Jo Bro”」
[The hit movie now playing in Edo. Even that man cried emotional tears.]
Why’s it have to be just before quitting time?
(整備員)なんだよ
もう退社時間だってのによ！
(整備員)なんか飛行中に
異物が 機体に取りついてるのが➡
Seems something alien attached itself to the fuselage during the flight.
確認されたんだと｡
Huh? You’re not suggesting an alien or something is stuck to it…?
(整備員)はぁ？ おいおい➡
えいりあんでも
取りついてんじゃねえだろうな｡
Which reminds me. Did you see “Alien vs. Yakuza”? Man, it was awesome…
(整備員)あっ そういや
見たか ｵﾒｴ！
『えいりあん VS やくざ』
すごかったよ～ あれ！
I haven’t seen the series since “Alien 2.”
(整備員)ｵﾚ えいりあんは
２以来 見てねえな｡
正直 あれはないんじゃない？
Really, it’s not that good, is it?
No, you’ve got to see it.
(整備員)いや 見てみって ｵﾒｴ！
The latest one’s awesome!
今度のは ｽｹﾞｴから｡
ものすげえ数の えいりあんと➡
There’s this army of aliens, right, and they fight a bunch of Jo Bro clones…
ものすげえ数の丈ｱﾆｷが 闘うんだ｡
どっちが勝っても
江戸に待つのは 滅びのみという｡
…and no matter which side wins, only death awaits them in Edo!
なんでだよ
なんで 丈ｱﾆｷで滅ぶんだよ｡
Why’s that? Why’s Edo going to be destroyed because of Jo Bro?
いやいや ｵﾒｴ｡ 正直 ｵﾚは
丈ｱﾆｷのほうが怖かったよ～！
You know what? I was actually more afraid of Jo Bro.
(整備員)そうかい じゃあ 丈ｱﾆｷが
機体に取りついてないことを➡
That so? Then let’s hope it’s not Jo Bro that’s stuck to the fuselage.
祈ろうや｡
ﾊｯﾊｯﾊ…！
(２人)ん？
ﾎﾝﾄに出た～！
(２人の悲鳴)
It’s for real!
Shut up! Keep your voices down!
(星海坊主)うるせえ！
でけえ声 出すんじゃねえ｡
I’ve got a hangover and my head is absolutely killing me!
二日酔いで
頭 ｶﾞﾝｶﾞﾝしてんだっつ～の｡
あぁ 気持悪い｡
なんで 地球まで来て えいりあん
退治せにゃならんのだ？
I come all the way to Earth and still I’ve got to exterminate Aliens.
(２人)ひぃっ！
ﾌﾝｯ！
(星海坊主)ったく
今回は ﾌﾟﾗｲﾍﾞｰﾄだってのに➡
For crying out loud…
This was supposed to be a personal trip.
おたくら 整備士か？
You guys mechanics?
There’s a good chance that monster’s main body has escaped into Edo.
ｺｲﾂの中にいた本体… 江戸に
逃げ込んでる可能性が高いぞ｡
(星海坊主)このままじゃ
江戸は えらいことになる｡
Edo’s in big trouble.
警察に 連絡つけてくれるか？
Would you tell the police for me?
星海坊主って言えば
わかるからよ｡
Just tell them Umibozu’s calling.
["Give a Thought to Planned Pregnancy"]
[TEL]
Hello? Odd Jobs.
(神楽)はい もしもし万事屋ｱﾙ｡
Hello. It’s me. Me.
[TEL](男)もしもし 拙者 拙者！
ｸﾞｽｯ…｡
(神楽)誰ｱﾙか？
[TEL]拙者だって！
Who are you?
It’s me! I’m in big trouble.
[TEL]今ちょっと
大変なことになってて ｸﾞｽｯ｡
(神楽)銀ちゃん？
[TEL]そうだよ
銀ちゃんだよ 銀ちゃん ｸﾞｽｯ｡
Is that you, Gin-chan?
That’s right. It’s Gin-chan… Gin-chan.
I got into an accident and hit a pregnant woman. I’m in deep trouble.
[TEL]さっき事故で妊婦 はねちゃって
大変なことに｡
(神楽)とどめさして
逃げてこいよ｡
Finish her off and run away.
What?! How could you say that? That’s awful!
[TEL]おい～！ なに言ってるの｡
ﾀﾞﾒだよ そんなこと言っちゃ!!
[TEL]とにかく 金が入り用なんだ｡
Anyway, I need money. If you don’t hurry, I’ll be arrested.
[TEL]早くしないと
拙者 捕まっちゃうよ！
(神楽)ﾏｼﾞでか！
Seriously?
I need you to immediately deposit the money to this bank account…
[Note: In Japanese, the word “deposit” sounds similar to the term that means “throwing rice.”]
[TEL]早く 指定する口座に
金を振り込んでくれ！
(ﾄｲﾚの流水音)
That hurt. I wiped too hard.
(銀時)ｱﾀﾀ… 拭き過ぎた｡
Man, we’ve got to get a bidet.
やっぱ ｼｬﾜｰﾄｲﾚつけねえと
ﾀﾞﾒだ これ｡
あらっ 今
誰か出ていかなかった？
Huh? Did somebody just leave?
Yeah. That was Kagura-chan.
(新八)あぁ 神楽ちゃんですよ｡
She went rushing out in a panic after taking a call.
なんか 電話とったあと
慌てて出て行きましたけど｡
What’s that about?
なんだ そりゃ｡
Must’ve been a call from her home. Maybe they want her to return.
実家からじゃないっすか？
帰ってこいって電話きたのかも｡
That’d be great. It’d be a lot quieter around here.
ｿｲﾂはいいなぁ｡ うるせえのが
いなくなって せいせいすらぃ｡
More importantly…
それよりこれ
銀さんも 気をつけてくださいよ｡
Gin-san, you gotta check this out.
拙者拙者詐欺？
The “It’s Me” con artist?
電話で 名前を名乗らずに➡
It’s a new scam where the con artist calls on the phone without saying their name,
拙者拙者を連呼して
近しい人を装い➡
just saying “It’s me” and letting you assume it’s someone you know.
Then they say they’re in trouble and need you to wire money to them.
今ﾋﾟﾝﾁだから 金が入り用なんだと
大金を振り込ませる➡
新手の詐欺です｡
ｱﾊﾊﾊ…！
ｵﾚは 誰がﾋﾟﾝﾁになろうが
振り込まねえぞ｡
I wouldn’t deposit money no matter who was in trouble.
Remember that, Shinpachi.
覚えとけ 新八｡
The only one who’d fall for that is some stupid girl with Amazonian strength.
んなもん 引っ掛かるのは
どっかの ﾊﾞｶな怪力娘だけ…｡
(２人)ん？
Umibozu? What’s that?
(沖田)星海坊主？
何でい そりゃ？
You don’t know, Okita-san? Everybody knows.
(隊士)んなことも
知らねえんすか？ 沖田さん｡
常識よ 常識｡
Let me see that.
(沖田)ちょ… ｵﾚにも見せてくれ｡
Hey, don’t push.
(隊士)押さないでくださいよ｡
Phew! Somebody reeks! Wash your underarms!
(隊士)ｸｻｯ！ 誰か臭いぞ ﾜｷ洗え｡
In simple terms, he’s an alien buster.
(隊士)早い話 えいりあんばすた～
というﾔﾂですよ｡
第一級危険生物を追い 駆逐する
宇宙の掃除人です｡
A space exterminator who hunts and eradicates the most dangerous aliens in the galaxy.
ﾔﾂは そのなかでも
最強と謳われる掃除人で➡
He’s celebrated as the strongest of all the exterminators.
いち掃除人でありながら
あちこちの惑星国家の政府にも➡
He has secret ties with planetary authorities everywhere.
顔がきく大物です｡
He’s a man who has traveled the stars and battled countless monsters.
(隊士)あまたの星を渡り
数多くのﾊﾞｹﾓﾉを 狩ってきた男｡
He’s known only as “Umibozu”… He’s a living legend.
ついたあだ名が星海坊主｡
生ける伝説ですよ｡
Ohh… So what’s a legend doing here?
ほぅ～ それで
その伝説が なぜここに？
Seems an alien escaped into Edo.
(隊士)なんでも えいりあんが
江戸に逃げ込んだとか｡
We appreciate you coming here to warn us.
(近藤)わざわざの ご忠告
感謝します｡
あとのことは 我々が
なんとかしますので ご安心を｡
We will handle it from here, so please rest assured.
しかし あれですな｡
However, I never thought I would meet the Umibozu. I am honored.
まさか あの星海坊主殿と
お会いできるとは➡
感激の極みであります｡
Are you here on Earth to hunt aliens?
地球へは やっぱり
えいりあん狩りですか？
(星海坊主)ｷﾉｺ狩りみたいな言い方
やめてくんない？
You say that like I’m hunting mushrooms!
I’m here on private business.
ﾔﾎﾞ用でね｡
I’m pursuing someone much more troublesome than any alien.
えいりあん なんぞより
よっぽど 手のかかるﾔﾂを➡
追ってきたのよ｡
ほぅ！
Someone who troubles even the famed Umibozu-dono?
星海坊主殿が
てこずるほどの相手とは➡
さては これですか？
A woman, I take it.
ﾌﾌﾌｯ 女には違いねえがな｡
She is indeed a woman. No question about that.
[Oedo Bank & Trust]
(神楽)ﾌﾝｯ ﾌﾝｯ…！
ふごぉ～！
Ma’am, what’re you doing?!
(銀行員)お客様～
ちょっと なにやってんのぉ！
I’m sorry. Gin-chan told me on the phone! He’ll get in trouble if I don’t “throw rice!”
すいませ～ん 早くふりこめないと
銀ちゃんが！
銀ちゃんが ﾌﾞﾀ箱に～！
Huh? Throw rice?
はぁ？ ふりこめ？
Miss, Miss…
お嬢さん お嬢さん
米 振るんじゃなくて➡
You don’t throw rice. Don’t you mean “deposit”?
振り込めなんじゃないの？
Anyway, I have to do this!
(神楽)とにかく
振り米ないといけないね！
No, you must be referring to “deposit”!
いや それ ｢振り込め｣だよ 絶対！
Don’t bother me, four eyes!
(神楽)うるさい！
あっち行ってろ ﾒｶﾞﾈ!!
(銀行員)ﾊﾊｯ お騒がせして
申し訳ありません｡
We’re sorry about the commotion.
Sir, how can I help you? Sir?
お客様 ご用件は？ お客様…？
(土方)なに 星海坊主？
What? Umibozu?
(土方)なんだって そんな大物が｡
ｸﾞｽｯ｡
What’s such a big shot doing here?
[無線](近藤)あれ ﾄｼ
なんかあったのか？
Huh? Toshi, is something wrong?
It’s nothing, Chief.
(原田)なんでもありませんよ局長｡
We have to act quickly or we’ll have a major problem.
[無線](近藤)江戸に 第一級危険生物が
入り込んだとのことだ｡
A parasitic alien has entered Edo.
[無線]寄生型えいりあん➡
ほうっておけば
大変なことになるぞ｡
Alien?
えいりあん？
It’s all over, Alien!!
えいりあんが
なんぼのもんじゃ～い！
Prepare for Samurai Justice!!
ここは 侍の国だぞ～！
Hey, Toshi, what’s going on? Did something happen?
[無線](近藤)おいﾄｼ どうした？
何か あったのか!?
Jo Bro, we shall avenge you!!
(土方)丈のｱﾆｷの敵じゃ～！
[無線]丈さんって 何かあったのか？
丈さんに 何かあったのか～!?
Jo-san? What happened? Did something happen to a guy named Jo-san?
Jo Bro, we love you!!
(原田)ﾋｶﾞｼの帝王じゃあ～！
I don’t entirely understand… but listen carefully.
なんだか よくわからんが➡
今から言うことを
よく聞いてくれ！
This alien can take over any organism—a dog, a cat— anything as its host.
寄生型えいりあんは 人間から犬猫
何にでも寄生する｡
知能は低いが 食料調達のために
なんでも狩る 危険なﾔﾂだ！
Its intelligence is low, but its adaptability makes it deadly!
[無線](近藤)寄生された者を
判別するには➡
The quickest way to tell if someone’s been taken over by it is to look at their face. There will be bruises.
顔を見るのが早い｡ ﾊﾟﾝﾀﾞを捜せ！
Look for a panda! The parasite’s host…
[無線]寄生された者の目の周囲には
ｸﾏのような黒いｱｻﾞが出る｡
will have black circles around their eyes.
[無線]いいか みんな ﾊﾟﾝﾀﾞを捜すんだ！
Understand, men? Look for a panda! We must…
[無線]被害が… 被害が出る前に
なんとしてでも食い止めるんだ！
stop it before it causes any damage. Look for a panda!
[無線]ﾊﾟﾝﾀﾞだ！ ﾊﾟﾝﾀﾞﾀﾞじゃねえぞ｡
ﾊﾟﾝﾀﾞだ!!
Not like…a real panda…you know.
[無線]いや 今の ｢だ｣は
そういう ｢だ｣じゃなくて！
(結野ｱﾅ)こちら 現在 銀行強盗が
立てこもっている➡
I’m at the Oedo Bank & Trust, where a robber has barricaded himself inside.
大江戸信用金庫前です｡
(結野ｱﾅ)あっ 今 犯人の顔が！
ひどいｸﾏです｡
We can see the robber’s face! What are those dark circles around his eyes?
寝不足でしょうか!?
He must be sleep deprived!
A panda.
ﾊﾟﾝﾀﾞﾀﾞ｡
Testing, testing…
(警官)あ～あ～… 犯人に告ぐ！
This is a message for the robber!
ｷﾐたちは 完全に包囲されている！
おとなしく出てきなさ～い!!
You are completely surrounded.
Come out peacefully.
We’re too late.
遅かったか…｡
えっ!?
What? You don’t mean that Kagura-chan did this?
まさか 神楽ちゃん？
これ 神楽ちゃんが!?
Kagura is responsible?
That’s right. She was tricked by the “It’s Me” scam and tried to deposit money.
そうだよ｡
拙者拙者詐欺に騙されて➡
金を振り込もうとしたは いいが
当然 金なんかあるわけねえだろ｡
But, of course, she doesn’t have any money. And that’s what led to this violent act.
そして こんな凶行に…｡
そんな… どうしよう｡
Oh no… What should we do?
ﾎﾞｸら どうすれば…｡ 銀さん？
What can we do?
Gin-san?
犯人に告ぐ！
This is a message for the robber…
…おい なにやってんだ ｷﾐ！
Hey, what’re you people doing?!
ｱｲﾂとは やり合っても
勝てる気がしねえが➡
I don’t think I can beat her, but if I don’t try to stop her, who will?
ｵﾚが止めずに 誰が止める｡
ﾔﾂの家族がいても
そうするはずさ｡
If her family were here, they’d do the same.
銀さん…｡ ﾎﾞｸも行きます！
G-Gin-san…
I’m in too.
(警官)危ないって！
It’s too dangerous!
Kagura-chan!
神楽ちゃん！
Our mistake.
(２人)間違えました｡
(野次馬)
うわぁ～っ！ ﾊﾞｹﾓﾉいたぁ～!!
A monster!
いや よかったな｡
Well… I’m glad… seems Kagura-chan isn’t the robber.
神楽ちゃん
犯人じゃなかったみたいだよ｡
そうですね｡
Yes, you’re right.
でも なんか
襲われてませんでした？
But wasn’t something attacking her?
あれじゃねえか？ 親父だろ あれ｡
That must’ve been, you know, her father.
電話っつうのは 親父からでよ
ここで 待ち合わせしてたんだよ｡
That call must’ve been from her father. They were meeting here.
あぁ そうか｡ 親子の抱擁か あれ｡
Oh, so that was her father giving her a big hug.
親子水入らずを ｼﾞｬﾏしちゃ…｡
They want time alone, just father and daughter. We really shouldn’t disturb their reunion…
銀ちゃん ひどいよ！
なんで 助けてくれないね!?
Gin-chan, that’s cruel. Why didn’t you rescue me?
(２人)だあぁ～っ!!
What’re you doing? What’s that all over you?! Is that your father’s guts!
なにしてんの お前！
なんか いっぱい ついてるぞ！
親父さんの内臓的なものが!!
I threw a lot of rice for you, Gin-chan.
私 銀ちゃんのために
いっぱい 振り込めしたよ｡
神父さんの件は どうなった？
ｶﾀついたか？
What happened to the priest? Did you settle it?
[Note: A play on the word ninpu meaning pregnant woman and shinpu meaning priest]
神父の件って なに？ お前
どんな騙され方したんだ おい！
What’s this about a priest? How did that guy scam you?!
ちょっと あれ 何なんだよ!?
ｵﾒｴの親父じゃねえのか!?
What is that?
Is that your dad?
(神楽)知らないよ！
ﾌﾗｯと やってきて➡
That’s not my dad!! It just appeared and started spewing all over the place.
勝手に ﾃﾞﾛﾃﾞﾛし始めたね！
まだ ﾃﾞﾛﾃﾞﾛやってるよ！
It’s still spewing!
(神楽)あぁっ！
(新八/銀時)だぁっ！
離せ！ 離せ!!
神楽ちゃん 離しなさい！ めっ!!
Let go! Let go!!
Bad Kagura-chan! Let go of us!
ﾍﾟｯ！ お前ら 全員 道連れじゃ！
I’m taking both of you with me!
(神楽)わっ！
(銀時/新八)あぁ～っ!!
お… いた いた｡
Oh, found you.
うぉりゃあ～っ!!
(えいりあんの叫び声)
おい あの傘…｡
Hey, that umbrella…
(星海坊主)捜したぞ 神楽｡
I’ve been looking for you… Kagura.
♪♪～
(神楽)ﾊﾟﾋﾟｰ…？
Pappy?
(新八/銀時)ﾊﾟ… ﾊﾟﾋﾟｰ!?
Pa…Pappy?!
[Starring Jo Otononaji]
ﾍｯ 冗談じゃねえよ｡
No way!
ﾃﾒｴの筋 曲げるくらいなら
死んだほうが ﾏｼだ！
I’d rather die than break my principles!
I was totally moved.
もう むっちゃ感動です！
(２人)丈ｱﾆｷ 最高！
Jo Bro is the best!
泣けました｡ 最高です｡
(泣き声)
Yes, I cried. It was the best.
(みんな)えいりあんが
なんぼのもんじゃい！
Aliens are scum!
えいりあんが
なんぼのもんじゃ～い!!
Aliens?! It’s all over!
＜生き残るのは
やくざか えいりあんか!?＞
Yakuza? Or aliens? Which one will survive?
Aliens vs Yakuza
[Aliens vs Yakuza]
[Now playing]
おい ﾂﾈよ 男だったら
背中で語れや｡
Hey, Otsune. A man talks with his back.
Testing, testing.
(沖田)あ～ あ～
えいりあんに告ぐ｡
This is a message for the alien.
(沖田)お前は
完全に 包囲されている｡
You are completely surrounded.
ﾑﾀﾞな抵抗はやめて おとなしく
投降しなさい えいりあん｡
Give up this pointless resistance and come out peacefully, alien.
故郷の おふくろさんも
泣いてるぞ｡
Your mother back in your hometown is crying!
そんな えいりあんにするために➡
She didn’t raise you to be this kind of alien.
産んだんじゃない ってな｡
どんな えいりあん？
What kind of alien is that?
It doesn’t matter if you’re an alien or human,
えいりあんだろうが 人間だろうが
母ちゃん泣かすﾔﾂは 最低だ｡
anyone who makes his mother cry is a loser. Right, mother?
ねぇ おふくろさん｡
何か言ってやってください｡
Say something.
What? She’s here? Its mother is here?
(山崎)えっ 来てんの？
おふくろさん 来てんの!?
Mommy doesn’t know you anymore…
お母さん もう知らないから！
お母さん…
もう ３年前の あのときから➡
Ever since that day three years ago, mommy wants to say…she no longer has a son!
息子は いないものだと…｡
(隊士たち)局長～！
Chief!
えいりあんが
なんぼのもんじゃ～い!!
You’re dead meat, Alien scum!
Totally dead!
(原田)なんぼのもんじゃい！
(隊士)いや➡
No, this isn’t an alien.
えいりあんじゃねえから これ！
局長 しっかり～！
Chief, speak to me!
はぁ… あっ｡
(山崎)誰か出てくるぞ！
Someone’s coming out.
Ready!
構え！
♪♪～
いいから来いってんだよ｡
Just come with me! I’ll treat you to a marron parfait!
あれだ…
ﾏﾛﾝﾊﾟﾌｪ 食わしてやっからな｡
(神楽)ちょっ… 離してよ！
離れて歩いてよ！
Let go! Don’t walk so close!
What’s the matter? Are you embarrassed to be with your father?!
(星海坊主)なんだ お父さんと
歩くのが 恥ずかしいのか？
どこだ？ どのへんが恥ずかしい？
What is it? What part of me is embarrassing?
具体的に言え｡
お父さん 直すから｡
Tell me and pappy will fix it!
It’s too late to fix it.
(神楽)もう
取り返しのつかないところだよ｡
(星海坊主)神楽ちゃん 人間には➡
Kagura-chan, there’s nothing a man can’t fix!
取り返しの
つかないことなんて ないぞ｡
I can make amends for any mistake!
どんな過ちも 必ず償える！
It’s impossible! Once your hair falls out, it never comes back!
(神楽)ﾑﾘだよ｡ 一度 死んだ毛根は
かえってこないよ｡
Excuse me, I’d like a marron parfait, too.
すみません
ﾎﾞｸも ﾏﾛﾝﾊﾟﾌｪいいっすかね？
いや ちょっと待て｡
No, wait a minute. Maybe I’ll have a fruit parfait, after all. What should I have?
やっぱ ﾌﾙｰﾂﾊﾟﾌｪにしよっかな｡
どうしよ｡
なに？
What?
星海坊主!?
Umibozu?!
Umibozu… What? He’s Kagura’s father?!
星海坊主って あの…
えっ 神楽ちゃんのお父さんが!?
Umibozu? What is that, some sort of phantom?
[Note: "bozu" means priest, and is slang for bald.]
星海坊主？ なにそれ 妖怪？
He’s not bald, but his hair is thinning.
坊主じゃねえぞ｡
うすらってるぞ 頭｡
おい うすらってるって なんだ｡
Hey, what do you mean by “thinning”?
I’m just thin on top.
人の頭を さすらってるみたいな
言い方するな｡
星海坊主といえば
銀河に 名をとどろかす➡
Umibozu is the fiercest Alien Buster ever.
最強の えいりあんはんた～…
さすらいの掃除屋っすよ｡
His name is known throughout galaxy. The wandering exterminator.
あ～ はいはい 聞いたことあるわ｡
うすらいの掃除屋｡
Oh, yeah, yeah, I’ve heard of him. The balding janitor.
おい…
うすらいの掃除屋って なんだ｡
It’s “buster”, not "janitor"!
ただの ﾀﾞﾒなおっさんじゃねえか｡
Who is this jerk?
ｶﾁﾝときた｡
おとうさん ｶﾁﾝときたよ｡
He makes your Pappy mad. Can I kill him?
ｶﾞﾁﾝと やっちゃって いい？
Calm down, Thinner.
落ち着くね ｳｽﾗｰ｡
ｳｽﾗｰって…｡
Thinner…? Huh? That sounds like “Winner,” so it might be cool.
あれ？ でも ﾊｽﾗｰみたいで
かっこいいかもな…｡
(神楽)ｳｽﾗｰ 紹介するね｡
こっちの ﾀﾞﾒなﾒｶﾞﾈが 新八ｱﾙ｡
Thinner, let me introduce you. This guy with the hopeless specs is Shinpachi.
ﾀﾞﾒって なに？
What do you mean, hopeless?
And this guy with the stupid fuzzy-head is Gin-chan.
(神楽)こっちの
ﾀﾞﾒなﾓｼﾞｬﾓｼﾞｬが 銀ちゃんｱﾙ｡
いや だから ﾀﾞﾒって なに？
What’s with the stupid?
私が こっちで
面倒みてやってる連中ね｡
These are the guys I’m looking after while on Earth.
挨拶するよろし｡
Please get along.
Hmph. Are you sure they weren’t planning something illegal?
ﾌﾝ なんか よからぬことでも
考えてたんじゃねえの？
夜兎の力を悪用しようって輩が
巷に あふれてるからな｡
The streets are overflowing with people who want to misuse the strength of the Yato.
What? What do you mean by “misuse”?
なんだぁ？
悪用って どういうことだ ｺﾗｧ｡
ﾃﾒｴの頭で ﾀﾞｲｺﾝでも
すりおろすことを指すのか？
You talking about grating a radish on your head?
A father who abandoned his daughter has no right to talk.
だいたい 長い間
娘 ほったらかしてた親父が➡
とやかく言えた義理かよ！
I’ve been hunting feverishly for her ever since
なんだぁ？ こちとら
必死に捜し回ったっつんだよ！
ちょっと 目 離したら
消えてたんだよ！
I took my eyes off her for a second and she disappeared.
難しいんだよ この年頃の娘は！
ｶﾞﾗｽ細工のように 繊細なんだよ！
Girls this age are difficult. They’re as fragile as a glass sculpture.
なに言ってやがんだ！
What’re you talking about? Your brain is as fragile as a glass sculpture!
ｶﾞﾗｽ細工のような
危なげな頭しやがって！
You talk big, with your big hair.
ﾃﾒｴ！ 今のうちだけだぞ
強気でいられるのは！
30過ぎたら 急に くるんだよ！
But, when you pass thirty, it’ll happen so quickly.
Before you know it, the follicle goddess will abandon you too!
いつのまにか 毛根の女神が
実家に帰ってるんだよ！
Come on, stop that, you two!
At any rate, I can’t leave my daughter in the hands of someone like you.
とにかく ﾃﾒｴのようなﾔﾂに
ｳﾁの娘は任せてられねえ！
神楽ちゃんは
ｵﾚが 連れて帰るからな！
I’m taking Kagura-chan home with me!
なに 勝手に決めてんだぁ!!
You don’t get to decide that!
神楽ちゃん なにすんの？
ﾄﾞﾒｽﾃｨｯｸ ﾊﾞｲｵﾚﾝｽ!?
Kagura-chan, there’s no excuse for domestic violence!
Pappy, you ignored your family and did whatever you pleased.
今まで 家庭 ほったらかして
好き勝手やってた ﾊﾟﾋﾟｰに➡
I don’t want you meddling in my life now.
今さら 干渉されたくないね｡
I don’t interfere in your life…so don’t interfere in mine!
ﾊﾟﾋﾟｰも勝手 私も勝手｡
I came to Earth on my own. I’ll go home on my own.
私 勝手に 地球 来た｡
帰るのも 勝手にするね｡
神楽ちゃん…｡
Kagura-chan…
Family is like a bird’s nest.
家族ってのは
鳥の巣のようなもんだ｡
鳥は いつでも
飛び続けられるわけじゃねえ｡
A bird can’t keep on flying forever.
帰る巣がなくなれば いずれ
地に落っこっちまうもんさ｡
If there’s no nest to go home to, she’ll eventually fall to the ground.
ﾊﾟﾋﾟｰは 渡り鳥…
巣なんて必要ないｱﾙ｡
Pappy, you’re a migratory bird. You don’t need a nest.
私も そう…｡
I’m the same way. I don’t need a nest; a wooden perch is enough.
巣なんて
止まり木があれば十分ね｡
(星海坊主)それじゃあ なんで
この止まり木に こだわる？
Then what’s so special about this wooden perch?
ここでしか得られねえもんでも
あるってのか？
Is there something that you can only get here?
また あそこに帰ったところで
何が得られるね？
What would I gain by going back home?
私は 好きな木に止まって
好きに 飛ぶね｡
I’ll perch wherever I like and fly from there.
ｶﾞｷが ﾅﾏ言ってんじゃねえぞ！
Kid! Don’t talk like you know it all.
ﾊｹﾞが いつまでも
ｶﾞｷだと思ってんじゃないね｡
You still think I’m a kid…Baldy?
あれ… 何？ この感じ｡
おい ちょっ…｡
Huh? What is this feeling?
Hey, they’re going to…
(神楽)ｳｧﾁｬｱｧ～！
Kagura-chan!
神楽ちゃん！
(２人)ｱﾁｮ～!!
(爆発音)
All right, carefully move it outside.
(土方)いいか？
丁重に 外に運び出してくれ｡
(沖田)土方さん
こんな気味の悪い死骸➡
Hijikata-san, what’re we going to use this nasty corpse for?
何に使うんですかい？
The Immigration officers said to bring it in.
入国管理局の連中が
持ってこいってさ｡
どっかの お偉いさんで
欲しがってるﾔﾂがいるんだとよ｡
Some VIP wants it, they said.
趣味の悪い野郎もいたもんだ｡
You’d think he could find something better to collect…
(沖田)しかし 星海坊主ってのは➡
Is this the kind of monster Umibozu always fights?
いつも こんなﾊﾞｹﾓﾉと
やり合ってんですかい？
(沖田)どっちがﾊﾞｹﾓﾉだか
わかりゃしねえや｡
Makes me wonder which one is the real monster.
And to think he’s that China girl’s father! Not exactly the family type.
(土方)おまけに
あの怪力娘の 親父だったとは➡
生活感のかけらもねえ
男だったが…｡
(近藤)男ってﾔﾂには ２種類ある｡
There are two kinds of men.
一つは
家族や仲間 自分の巣を守り➡
One is the protective type who seeks to protect his home and family.
安寧を求める防人ﾀｲﾌﾟ｡
もう一つは 巣から出て
獲物を求めてさすらう狩人ﾀｲﾌﾟだ｡
The other is the hunter type who leaves that home in search of prey.
(近藤)あの男の目は
狩人というより 獣に近い｡
In that man's eyes, I see the hunter.
おとなしく巣に
おさまってるﾀﾏでは あるまいよ｡
But even more… I see a beast. He’s not the type that can stay peacefully at home.
(近藤)もしかしたら あの娘➡
I’m afraid that girl has lived a lonely life until now…
今まで 寂しい思いをして
生きてきたのかもしれんな…｡
(爆発音)
(通行人)うわぁ～!!
なんだ？ なんだ!?
What’s that?!
(通行人)何だ？ あれ｡ 人間か？
What are they? Are they even human?!
ｸｯ…｡ だいたい 嫁入り前の娘が➡
Do you think I’d allow my unmarried daughter
男と同棲なんて
許されると思っているのか!?
to live with a man?!
そういうところから
できちゃった結婚とか➡
That’s how you get
a marriage forced by pregnancy!
ただれた展開が
始まっていくんだよ！
私 そんな
ふしだらな女じゃないね！
I’m not a loose woman!
だいたい ﾏﾐｰ
できちゃった結婚だったって➡
And anyway, isn’t that how you married mommy?!
言ってたよ！
あのｱﾏ!!
That bitch! She told you that?!
子供に
何てこと しゃべってんだ～！
だから ﾊﾟﾋﾟｰに とやかく言われる
筋合いはないね！
You’ve got no right to preach, Pappy!
あるね！
I do!
I won’t let you make the same mistake I did!
(星海坊主)同じ過ちを
繰り返してはならねえ！
♪♪～
ｳｧﾁｬｱ～！
うっ！
おりゃあ～！
(人々の悲鳴)
ﾌｯ…｡
ｸﾞｯ… ふっ！
もう ほっといてよ！
Leave me alone already!
今まで ずっと
ほったらかしだったくせに！
That’s all you’ve ever done anyway!!
私が どこで どう生きるかなんて
私が 自分で決めるね！
So I’ll decide for myself where and how I’ll live!
Seems you really like this wooden perch.
(星海坊主)よほど この止まり木が
気に入ってるらしいな｡
(星海坊主)
だったら なおさら去るがいい｡
Then all the more reason you should leave it.
忘れたか？
我らのなかの獣の本能を…｡
Have you forgotten the beast blood that runs through our veins?
獲物を求めてさまよう
夜兎の本能を…｡
The Yato instinct that makes us roam in search of prey?
しょせん ｵﾚたちは
戦場でしか生きられない獣｡
We are just beasts that can only live on the battlefield.
安寧に身をおいたところで
どうだ？ このｻﾞﾏは…｡
What happens when you put that beast in a peaceful place?
(星海坊主)
我を忘れ 破壊し 傷つけ…｡
You forget who you are…
become self-destructive, hurt yourself…
(星海坊主)このまま いけば➡
Stay here, and you’ll snap this wooden perch in half.
お前は 自分で この止まり木を
折ることになるだろう｡
ここが好きなら去れ！
If you love this place, then leave it.
家に帰りたくねえなら
ｵﾚと来い！
If you don’t want to come home, then come with me.
ここは お前の居場所じゃねえ｡
This isn’t the place for you. This isn’t the sky we should fly in.
ｵﾚたちが
飛んでいい空じゃねえんだよ｡
ｲﾔｱﾙ！
No. I don’t want to live a life where I just give up.
私は そんなあきらめたような
生き方 したくないね！
私は ここで変わるね｡
I’m going to change here. I know if I stay here, I can change.
ここにいれば
変われる気がするね!!
(神楽)
銀ちゃんたちと一緒にいるね！
I’ll stay with Gin-chan and the others.
銀ちゃん？ あの野郎か…｡
Gin-chan? That guy? What can a bum like him do?
あんな ﾁｬﾗﾝﾎﾟﾗﾝに
何ができるってんだ？
しかたねえ…｡
You leave me no choice…
だったら
力ずくでも連れてくぜ！
Then I’ll take you with me by force.
(神楽)うわっ！
(神楽)うっ…｡
(神楽)銀ちゃん！
Gin-chan!
Mommy!
(娘)お母さん！
ったく…｡
What is it with you people?!
なに やってんだ！ ﾃﾒｴら｡
Gin-chan, I…
銀ちゃん 私…｡
何のﾏﾈだ？
What do you think you’re doing?
Don’t be sticking your nose into a family argument.
親子ｹﾞﾝｶに
ｸﾋﾞ突っ込むなんざ ﾔﾎﾞだぞ｡
That was another wild fight.
また派手に暴れやがったな！
とんだ親子だ…
ｶｴﾙの子は やっぱりｶｴﾙだな｡
You and your daughter are a pair! Like father like daughter, huh?
帰れ…｡
Go home.
お前には やっぱり
地球は狭いんじゃねえの？
The Earth’s too small for you, after all.
いい機会だ…
親父と一緒に行けよ｡
I think we can all see that now. Go home with your father.
これで さよならとしようや｡
Let’s make this good-bye.
What? Why? Why are you saying that?
なんで…
なんで そんなこと言うね｡
私 絶対 帰らないね｡
I’m never going back… I’ll stay…forever…with you and the others…
ずっと…
ずっと銀ちゃんたちと…｡
ちょっと待って！
やめろ!!
Wait…
Stop it!
よく考えろよ｡
Think about it. This isn’t where you belong, is it?
お前の居場所は
ここじゃねえだろ？
♪♪～
なんで… なんで…｡
Why…?
なんで…｡
[Preview]
You fired her?! You fired Kagura-chan?!
Does that mean she went home together with her father?!
Gin-san, have you ever thought about Kagura-chan’s feelings?
The next episode: "You Can't Judge a Movie by Its Title."
Third year, class Z, Ginpachi-sensei
[Third Year, Class Z, Ginpachi-sensei!]
Stand! Bow! Take your seats!
For today's lesson, I'd like to explain the difference between “Alien” and “Amanto”.
Sensei, I think the spelling for Alien is “Alien” not “Aliyan”.
Shut up, this is more sophisticated and trendy.
In the first place, I don’t want someone who can’t even speak proper Japanese to point that out.
OK everyone, open the brochure for “Alien vs Yakuza”.
Sensei, I have misty eyes and I can’t read this.
Please avenge Jo Bro.
Go to the nurse’s office and get a mayonnaise injection or something.
First of all, Aliens are…
Sensei!
I found out I am really alien.  What should I do?
Go home and have a talk with your mom.
Sensei, I’m hungry. Why don’t we finish this class?
♪♪～
Sensei has decided to have curry for lunch, so no.
What do you mean by that?
(近藤)起立！ 礼！ 着席!!
It’s okay. There was no meaning from the very beginning.
Okay, “Alien vs Yakuza” is now playing in theaters, so go and watch it, everyone.
は～い じゃあ 今日は➡
えいりあんと天人との
違いについて勉強するぞ｡
Okay.
(神楽)先生！ そこの字➡
I’m absolutely going to watch this movie.
[The End]
｢や｣じゃなくて
｢あ｣だと思いま～す｡
[Movie “Alien vs Yakuza”. Hasegawa is working part time at the movie theater.]
うるせえよ～！
こっちのほうが ｵｼｬﾚなんだよ｡
[Skit “Gin-san vs Sadaharu”. Movies are such a tough business.]
流行ってんだよ！
だいたい日本語も
ろくにしゃべれないﾔﾂに➡
そんなとこ
ﾂｯｺまれたくねえっての！
よ～し それじゃあ➡
『えいりあん VS やくざ』の
ﾊﾟﾝﾌﾚｯﾄを開け！
(土方)先生…
涙でかすんで文字が読めません｡
丈のｱﾆｷの仇を討ってください｡
お前は 保健室 行って
ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞでも注射してもらえ！
まず
えいりあんっていうのはだな…｡
(近藤)先生！ 実はﾎﾞｸ
えいりあんだったんですけど…｡
どうすればいいでしょう？
実家に帰って➡
お母さんに相談しろ！
(沖田)先生 お腹が空いたんで
授業 終わりにしませんか？
先生 お昼は
ｶﾚｰと決めているからﾀﾞﾒだ｡
意味が わかりません｡
いいんだよ｡
最初から意味なんてないんだから｡
じゃあ 『えいりあん VS やくざ』
絶賛上映中だから➡
みんな 見にいけよ｡
(みんな)は～い！
絶対 見に行こう｡
《試合は 同点のまま最終回｡
ﾂｰｱｳﾄ満塁｡
ｶｳﾝﾄは ｽﾘｰﾎﾞｰﾙ ﾂｰｽﾄﾗｲｸ》